<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0 on Data Science Studio</title>
    <link>/publication_types/0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 0 on Data Science Studio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication_types/0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>Adding a New PostBlog AuthorsNew Post TemplateRequired ComponentsCreate Summary Image From TemplateCreate Summary Text and LinkEditorial TeamFlagged as ReviewerActing AdminMerge RequestThis is a guide detailing how you can deploy your article to be featured on the DSS Blog. All posts are peer reviewed by two members of the DSS editorial team. Whether you are a new member, part of the editorial team, or an Acting Admin, this guide will serve as a road map for blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to DSS Blogs</title>
      <link>/post/welcome-to-dss-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-to-dss-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to DSS Blogs, a peer-reviewed blogging journal about reproducible analytics, functional graphing, statistical modeling, and data visualization.
This working group also reports on the activities of the Data Science Studio at the Institute of Aging and Lifelong Health, University of Victoria. If you are interested in being featured on the DSS Blogs, please consult our How to Contribute guide detailing how you can submit your blogpost for the peer review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 1 - Intro &amp; Workflow</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-17-a-scientist-guide-to-r-part-1-intro-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-17-a-scientist-guide-to-r-part-1-intro-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will be the first of many blog posts for new researchers and science program students/trainees on how to use R as an analytical and productivity tool in the process of conducting scientific research.Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origins of DSS</title>
      <link>/post/dss-origin-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dss-origin-story/</guid>
      <description>The Data Science Studio (DSS) was formed to promote sound practices of longitudinal modeling in health research and facilitate collaboration between academic researchers and health sytem organizations. This working group was conceived and launched by Ken Moselle, Scott Hofer, and Andriy Koval.
In fall 2014, Scott Hofer organized a colloquium series at the Institute on Aging and Lifelong Health - then “Centre on Aging” - with focus on reproducible methods and applications in aging research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox and Toolsets of Reproducible Research</title>
      <link>/talk/2014f-coag-colloquium/2014-10-10-toolbox-toolset-reproducible-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2014f-coag-colloquium/2014-10-10-toolbox-toolset-reproducible-research/</guid>
      <description>The lecture introduces reproducible research and demonstrates digital self-publishing with RStudio and Git (Hub). The skills described and emphasized in this workflow include data manipulation, graph production, statistical modeling, and dynamic reporting. A series of four talks discusses each skill and gives examples of possible implementations in R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>