<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Data Science Studio</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Data Science Studio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Florida Demographic Growth</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-27-florida-demographic-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-27-florida-demographic-growth/</guid>
      <description>This blogposts shows how to extract population estimates data reported by the Florida Department of Health and prepare them for analysis, specifically, for exploring the trends in demograph growth between 2006 and 2020</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifold Regression (part 1)</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-26-manifold-regression-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-26-manifold-regression-part1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the world of manifold regression! In part 1 we will introduce the basic concepts, overview the theory behind regression on manifolds, develop an intuition for these models, and discuss their applications.
Read full post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.1 - Data Transformation - Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The 4th post in the Scientist’s Guide to R series introduces data transformation techniques useful for wrangling/tidying/cleaning data. Specifically, we will be learning how to use the 6 core functions (and a few others) from the popular dplyr package, perform similar operations in base R, and chain operations with the pipe operator (%&amp;gt;%) to streamline the process. Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop for Beginners</title>
      <link>/post/andkov/2019-11-26-graphing-models-in-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/andkov/2019-11-26-graphing-models-in-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>The workshop introduces R and RStudio and makes the case for project-oriented workflows for applied data analysis. Using logistic regression on Titanic data as an example, the participants will learn to communicate statistical findings more effectively, and will evaluate the advantages of using computational notebooks in RStudio to disseminate the results</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.0 - basic operations and data structures</title>
      <link>/post/2019-08-06-asgr-part-2-0-basic-operations-and-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-08-06-asgr-part-2-0-basic-operations-and-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>As the third post in the Scientist’s Guide to R series (click here for the 1st post), we advance to the brink of the next major stage of the data analysis with R process: cleaning and transforming data. However, before we can clean or transform anything we will need to know how to do a few basic things and familiarize ourselves with some common data structures in R, which are the topics of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categories of research</title>
      <link>/post/categories-of-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/categories-of-research/</guid>
      <description>30-50 words</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to DSS Blogs</title>
      <link>/post/welcome-to-dss-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-to-dss-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to DSS Blogs, a peer-reviewed blogging journal about reproducible analytics, functional graphing, statistical modeling, and data visualization.
This working group also reports on the activities of the Data Science Studio at the Institute of Aging and Lifelong Health, University of Victoria. If you are interested in being featured on the DSS Blogs, please consult our How to Contribute guide detailing how you can submit your blogpost for the peer review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide detailing how you can deploy your article to be featured on the DSS Blog. All published posts are peer reviewed by two members of the DSS editorial team. Whether you are a new member, part of the editorial team, or an Acting Admin, this guide will serve as a road map to create and promote posts on DSS Blogs. ————–
Table of ContentAdding a New PostBlog AuthorsNew Post TemplateRequired ComponentsCreate Summary Image From TemplateCreate Summary Text and LinkEditorial TeamFlagged as ReviewerActing AdminMerge RequestAdding a New PostPlease note that this post assumes that you have:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Real-world” de-identification of linked Electronic Health Records</title>
      <link>/post/2019-07-16-data-de-identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-07-16-data-de-identification/</guid>
      <description>Linking health records is key to innovation in health care. At the same time linkage poses major challenges for disclosing patient data to researchers. The presentation proposes a methodology for structuring risk assessment of high-dimensional linked data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Target Information Architecture</title>
      <link>/post/2019-07-11-target-information-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-07-11-target-information-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Target Information Architecture (TIA) is an graphical rendering of answers to a series of linked questions relating to analytic products from data to support the functions performed by persons, providers or programs within a health system. We argue that a developed TIA is a necessary condition to guide the translation of health service analytics back into a health service system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 1 - Importing Data</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-22-asgr-part-1-getting-data-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-22-asgr-part-1-getting-data-into-r/</guid>
      <description>The second post in the Scientist’s Guide to R series covers everything you need to know to get started with importing data from a variety of sources (.csv, .txt, .xlsx, etc) into R. Click here to read the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Suppress for Release - CAHSPR, Halifax</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-26-suppress-for-release-cahspr-halifax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-26-suppress-for-release-cahspr-halifax/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, the Observatory for Population &amp;amp; Public Health of British Columbia launched the Chronic Disease Dashboard, an online reporting tool designed to address the gap in surveillance of chronic diseases. To protect against re-identification risks, the Ministry of Health required redacting small counts prior to releasing disease rates into public domain. These preparations, when conducted manually, have proven to be arduous, time consuming, and prone to human error. This paper gives the overview of the workflow for automated suppression of small cells and demonstrates key data operations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 1 - Intro &amp; Workflow</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-17-asgr-part-0-basic-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-17-asgr-part-0-basic-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will be the first of many blog posts for new researchers and science program students/trainees on how to use R as an analytical and productivity tool in the process of conducting scientific research.Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origins of DSS</title>
      <link>/post/dss-origin-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dss-origin-story/</guid>
      <description>The Data Science Studio (DSS) was formed to promote sound practices of longitudinal modeling in health research and facilitate collaboration between academic researchers and health sytem organizations. This working group was conceived and launched by Ken Moselle, Scott Hofer, and Andriy Koval.
In fall 2014, Scott Hofer organized a colloquium series at the Institute on Aging and Lifelong Health - then “Centre on Aging” - with focus on reproducible methods and applications in aging research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.1 - Data Transformation - Part 2</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In the 5th post of the Scientist’s Guide to R series we explore using the tidyr package to reshape data. You’ll learn all about splitting and combining columns and how to do wide to long or long to wide transformations. Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latex labels for ggplot graphs</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-13-easy-latex-titles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-13-easy-latex-titles/</guid>
      <description>The post demonstrates how to create Latex titles for reproducible graphs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>