<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reproducible Research on Data Science Studio</title>
    <link>/categories/reproducible-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reproducible Research on Data Science Studio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/reproducible-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 3.0 - exploring data with elucidate</title>
      <link>/post/2020-12-07-asgr-part-3-0-exploring-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-12-07-asgr-part-3-0-exploring-data/</guid>
      <description>This post dives into the elucidate package and how it can help you explore data using sets of functions for interrogating, describing, visualising, interacting with, and correcting data. This is a key stage of any analysis where errors are found and interesting relationships begin to appear. Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.5 - dates &amp; times</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-29-asgr-part-2-5-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-08-29-asgr-part-2-5-dates/</guid>
      <description>Dates/times are the last type of data you’ll probably work with on a fairly regular basis. This post will show you how to use the lubridate tidyverse package in R so you’ll know how to handle dates &amp;amp; times when you encounter them. Click here to read the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florida Suicides (2) - Youth Trends</title>
      <link>/post/andkov/2020-08-30-florida-suicide-2-youth-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/andkov/2020-08-30-florida-suicide-2-youth-trends/</guid>
      <description>Graphing the trends of suicides in Florida from 2006 to 2017 among youth between 10 and 24 years of age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.4 - factors</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-29-asgr-part-2-4-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-08-29-asgr-part-2-4-factors/</guid>
      <description>Factors are one of the two remaining types of data you’ll encounter on a fairly regular basis. This post will show you how to use the forcats tidyverse package in R so you’ll know how to handle factors when you encounter them. Click here to read the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.3 - strings</title>
      <link>/post/2020-06-28-asgr-part-2-3-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-06-28-asgr-part-2-3-strings/</guid>
      <description>Being able to work with character strings is an essential skill in data analysis and science. In this post we’ll learn a few of the ways in which the stringr package and regular expressions (AKA “regex” or “regexps”) makes working with strings in R considerably easier. Click here to read the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florida Suicides (1) - General Trends</title>
      <link>/post/andkov/2020-04-26-florida-suicide-1-general-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/andkov/2020-04-26-florida-suicide-1-general-trends/</guid>
      <description>Graphing the trends of suicides in Florida from 2006 to 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.2 - Joining Data</title>
      <link>/post/2020-03-29-asgr-part-2-2-joining-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-03-29-asgr-part-2-2-joining-data/</guid>
      <description>Out in the real world you may often find yourself working with data from multiple sources. It will probably be stored in separate files and you’ll need to combine them before you can attempt to answer any of your research questions. Click here to learn how you can combine data frames using a set of dplyr functions called joins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.1 - Data Transformation - Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The 4th post in the Scientist’s Guide to R series introduces data transformation techniques useful for wrangling/tidying/cleaning data. Specifically, we will be learning how to use the 6 core functions (and a few others) from the popular dplyr package, perform similar operations in base R, and chain operations with the pipe operator (%&amp;gt;%) to streamline the process. Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop for Beginners</title>
      <link>/post/andkov/2019-11-26-graphing-models-in-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/andkov/2019-11-26-graphing-models-in-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>The workshop introduces R and RStudio and makes the case for project-oriented workflows for applied data analysis. Using logistic regression on Titanic data as an example, the participants will learn to communicate statistical findings more effectively, and will evaluate the advantages of using computational notebooks in RStudio to disseminate the results</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.0 - basic operations and data structures</title>
      <link>/post/2019-08-06-asgr-part-2-0-basic-operations-and-data-structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-08-06-asgr-part-2-0-basic-operations-and-data-structures/</guid>
      <description>As the third post in the Scientist’s Guide to R series (click here for the 1st post), we advance to the brink of the next major stage of the data analysis with R process: cleaning and transforming data. However, before we can clean or transform anything we will need to know how to do a few basic things and familiarize ourselves with some common data structures in R, which are the topics of this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 1 - Importing Data</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-22-asgr-part-1-getting-data-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-22-asgr-part-1-getting-data-into-r/</guid>
      <description>The second post in the Scientist’s Guide to R series covers everything you need to know to get started with importing data from a variety of sources (.csv, .txt, .xlsx, etc) into R. Click here to read the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Suppress for Release - CAHSPR, Halifax</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-26-suppress-for-release-cahspr-halifax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-26-suppress-for-release-cahspr-halifax/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, the Observatory for Population &amp;amp; Public Health of British Columbia launched the Chronic Disease Dashboard, an online reporting tool designed to address the gap in surveillance of chronic diseases. To protect against re-identification risks, the Ministry of Health required redacting small counts prior to releasing disease rates into public domain. These preparations, when conducted manually, have proven to be arduous, time consuming, and prone to human error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 0 - Intro &amp; Workflow</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-17-asgr-part-0-basic-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-17-asgr-part-0-basic-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will be the first of many blog posts for new researchers and science program students/trainees on how to use R as an analytical and productivity tool in the process of conducting scientific research.Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASGR: 2.1 - Data Transformation - Part 2</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-12-30-asgr-part-2-1-data-transformation-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In the 5th post of the Scientist’s Guide to R series we explore using the tidyr package to reshape data. You’ll learn all about splitting and combining columns and how to do wide to long or long to wide transformations. Click here for the full post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latex labels for ggplot graphs</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-13-easy-latex-titles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-13-easy-latex-titles/</guid>
      <description>The post demonstrates how to create Latex titles for reproducible graphs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>