<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Data Science Studio</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Data Science Studio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifold Regression (part 2)</title>
      <link>/post/mrparker909/2020-03-16-manifold-regression-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mrparker909/2020-03-16-manifold-regression-part2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the world of manifold regression! In part 2 we will apply manifold regression to a case study involving fMRI brain imaging data using R and MGLMRiem. See part 1 for an introduction to these models.
Read full post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifold Regression (part 1)</title>
      <link>/post/2020-01-26-manifold-regression-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-01-26-manifold-regression-part1/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the world of manifold regression! In part 1 we will introduce the basic concepts, overview the theory behind regression on manifolds, develop an intuition for these models, and discuss their applications.
Read full post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to DSS Blogs</title>
      <link>/post/welcome-to-dss-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-to-dss-blogs/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to DSS Blogs, a peer-reviewed blogging journal about reproducible analytics, functional graphing, statistical modeling, and data visualization.
This working group also reports on the activities of the Data Science Studio at the Institute of Aging and Lifelong Health, University of Victoria. If you are interested in being featured on the DSS Blogs, please consult our How to Contribute guide detailing how you can submit your blogpost for the peer review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-contribute/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide detailing how you can deploy your article to be featured on the DSS Blog. All published posts are peer reviewed by two members of the DSS editorial team. Whether you are a new member, part of the editorial team, or an Acting Admin, this guide will serve as a road map to create and promote posts on DSS Blogs. ————–
Table of ContentAdding a New PostBlog AuthorsNew Post TemplateRequired ComponentsCreate Summary Image From TemplateCreate Summary Text and LinkEditorial TeamFlagged as ReviewerActing AdminMerge RequestAdding a New PostPlease note that this post assumes that you have:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>